Guide to the Witness to a Possibility records, 1968-1987 MS2345
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Witness to a Possibility (WTAP): Black Theater Movement in Washington, DC
circa 1960s - circa 1990s
1980-1986
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2345
4.5 Linear Feet 6 doument boxes and one oversized box
This collection contains audio cassettes, posters, correspondence, and publications related to the Witness To A Possibility (WTAP) project to document the Black Theater movement that took place in Washington, D.C., between 1968 and 1976. The Witness to a Possibility project was carried out in the 1980s by Howard University Professor Vera J. Katz and her former student, Taquiena Boston. The two worked together to collect documents and to conduct oral histories with many of the writers, actors, and directors for such theater programs as Black Repertory Theater and the Howard Players.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains audio cassettes, posters, correspondence, and publications related to the Witness To A Possibility (WTAP) project to document the Black Theater movement in Washington, D.C.
Arrangement
Organized into 2 series: Papers and Audio cassettes and ephemera.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Taquiena Boston, 2015 (Accession 2015.056)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Witness to a Possibility project documents the Black Theater movement that took place in Washington, D.C., between 1968 and 1976. The Black Theater movement represents a significant cultural landmark in the history of both theater and Washington, D.C.
The Black Theater movement was driven forward by significant events that profoundly affected the black community, such as the assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., the Vietnam War, and the general racial injustices in American society. The movement arose as a means to document the historical past of black people and as a way to address the issues and concerns of the community.
The Witness to a Possibility project was carried out in the 1980s by Howard University Professor Vera J. Katz and her former student, Taquiena Boston. The two worked together to collect documents and to conduct oral histories with many of the writers, actors, and directors for such theater programs as Black Repertory Theater and the Howard Players.
Duke Ellington School of the Arts; Howard University; Black theater--United States--History; African American history; Malone, Mike; Truitt, Quay Barnes; Austin, Joy Ford
- Papers, circa 1960s - circa 1990s; Series 1; 6 document boxes
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains posters, correspondence, and publications related to the Witness To A Possibility (WTAP) project to document the Black Theater movement in Washington, D.C.
  Howard University; Duke Ellington School of the Arts; Malone, Mike; Truitt, Quay Barnes; Austin, Joy Ford
  - Allen, Debbie, 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Debbie, 1979-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Paul, 1972-1974; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clearance forms [project information], 1968-1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    This folder contains a significant amount of background about the project, chapter outline for the book, and biographical information about the participants.
  - Correspondence, 1981-1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and news articles, 1985-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Clinton Turner, 1970-1975; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - DC Black Repertory Company, 1967-1977; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - DC Repertory Dance Company, 1975-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - DC Community Humanities Council, 1985-1986; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dickerson, Glenda, 1981-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dodson, Owen, 1977-1984; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Interviews and news articles, 1972-1986; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Interviews and expenses, 1968-1987; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Interviews and news articles, 1981-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jamaica, 1964; Series 1 (Box 7, Poster 4)
  - Malone, Mike, 1976-1983; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - News articles, 1969-1976; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - News articles, 1975-1981; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - News articles and correspondence, 1966-1981; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - News articles and correspondence, 1977-1992; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - News articles and programs, 1971-1983; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Programs and correspondence, 1971-1986; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Programs and correspondence, 1985-1987; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Programs and news articles, 1968-1987; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Programs and news articles, 1975-1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Programs and news articles, 1979-1990; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Publisher proposal packet, 1968-1976; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Puttin on the Mask, 1979; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Resumes and news articles, 1975-1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sankofa, 1982; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sheet music, undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Slides, circa 1965-1985; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Black Play, 1982; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Tiger, Tiger, Burning Bright, undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Print 1)
  - Traynor, Eleanor, 1976-1980; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Truitt, Quay B., circa 1975-1985; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Unknown promotional photo, Series 1 (Box 7, Print 2)
  - Unknown promotional photo, Series 1 (Box 7, Print 3)
  - WCA/Ellington, 1970-1982; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Audio cassettes and ephemera, circa 1960s - circa 1990s; 1980-1986; Series 2; 1 document boxes
  This series contains audio cassettes and a t-shirt related to the Witness To A Possibility (WTAP) project to document the Black Theater movement in Washington, D.C.
  Howard University; Duke Ellington School of the Arts; Austin, Joy Ford; Truitt, Quay Barnes; Malone, Mike
  - Advisory Committee Meeting, May 27, 1986 AAMA, Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 1)
  - Ajamu, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 2)
  - Allen, Paul, 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 3)
  - Ambush, Benny, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 4)
  - Ambush, Benny, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 5)
  - Brown, Charles, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 6)
  - Chandler, Brian, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 7)
  - Daugherty, Kenneth, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 8)
  - Daugherty, Kenneth, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 9)
  - Davis, Clinton T., 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 10)
  - Davis, Clinton, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 11)
  - Davis, Clinton, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 12)
  - Dodson, Owen, 1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 13)
  - Gravatt, Lynda, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 14)
  - Gravatt, Lynda, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 15)
  - Hooks, Robert, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 16)
  - Hooks, Bobby, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 17)
  - Reagon, Bernice, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 18)
  - Katz, Vera J., 1989; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 19)
  - Katz, Vera, 1974; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 20)
  - Katz, Vera and Taquiena Boston, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 21)
  - Katz, Vera, and Taquiena Boston, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 22)
  - Katz, Vera, 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 23)
  - LeBlanc, Whitney, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 24)
  - Maillard, Carol Lynn, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 25)
  - Malone, Mike, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 26)
  - Malone, Mike, 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 27)
  - Perry, Shaunelle, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 28)
  - Robinson, Louise, 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 29)
  - Shepherd, Kiki, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 30)
  - Shepherd McAlpin, Von Gretchen, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 31)
  - Shepherd McAlpin, Von Gretchen, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 32)
  - Shepherd McAlpin, Von Gretchen, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 33)
  - Traylor, Dr. Eleanor W., 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 34)
  - Traylor, Dr. Eleanor W., 1982; Series 2; Tape is damaged and cannot be played or digitized on Special Collections equipment. (Box 6, Cassette 35)
  - Walker, Joseph A., 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 36)
  - Walker, Joseph A., 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 37)
  - Walker, Philip, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 38)
  - Walker, Phil, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 39)
  - Wesley, Richard, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 40)
  - Wesley, Richard, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Cassette 41)
  - Shirt - "Everyman Street Theatre Co. presents God is [illegible] Streets Today", undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Item 1)